<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>DavidCraddock.Games</title>
    <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DavidCraddock.Games</description>
    <image>
      <title>DavidCraddock.Games</title>
      <url>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/mugshot.png</url>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/mugshot.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>David Paul Craddock</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:40:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Negative Gamers Annoy Me</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/negative-gamers-annoy-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 15:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/negative-gamers-annoy-me</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I am unusual, but I don&amp;rsquo;t get angry generally about new games that I buy. If I don&amp;rsquo;t like them, I don&amp;rsquo;t just play them. I have tons of games that I don&amp;rsquo;t like. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s the same as buying a book. I do not feel &amp;lsquo;ripped off&amp;rsquo; if I do not enjoy the book, I realise that I am paying for the development of the game and the hundreds (often thousands) of man hours that have gone into playing it. I realise that all art is subjective, and everyone has different &amp;rsquo;takes&amp;rsquo; on things - so I don&amp;rsquo;t try and tell other people what they might or might not enjoy, I just report what I enjoy (and I usually only write reviews for games I really like).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaming Collection Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/gaming-collection-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/?p=5</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve accumalated physical games, physical gaming consoles, controllers and computers over the years, it&amp;rsquo;s become more and more important to have some &amp;lsquo;rules&amp;rsquo; of what I collect, how I collect, and how I play the games I collect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a few exceptions for games which are some of my favourite games of all time, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to buy physical copies of any games. I want to keep as much digital as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Ultimate Yet Affordable Neo Geo Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/neo-geo-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 03:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/?p=5666</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want a proper Neo Geo console, but they are ridiculously expensive, even if you buy one and mod it, and don&amp;rsquo;t pay for the cartridges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So therefore I have looked at the best emulation possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having experimented with various different ways of playing Neo Geo games, including emulation on PC, playing them on the Evercade, mobile emulation on a Ambernic device, I have found my favourite way to play Neo Geo games that I can afford.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 player Mad Dog Mccree with Sinden Light Gun on PC</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/mad-dog-mcree-sinden-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/?p=7</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is how I got Mad Dog Mccree, the 1990 American Laser Game, working with two Sinden light guns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;software-required&#34;&gt;Software Required&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mad Dog Mcree 2 player HD enhanced ROM &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/hypseus_singe_maddog-hd_2p&#34;&gt;https://archive.org/details/hypseus_singe_maddog-hd_2p&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DirtBagXon&amp;rsquo;s version of hypseus-singe American Laser Game compatible emulator &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/DirtBagXon/hypseus-singe&#34;&gt;https://github.com/DirtBagXon/hypseus-singe&lt;/a&gt; - you will specifically need to download the portable version version &amp;lsquo;2.11.3&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gojidan&amp;rsquo;s bezels for the American Laser Games - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gojidan/hypseus-singe-bezels&#34;&gt;https://github.com/gojidan/hypseus-singe-bezels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard 2.07 beta Sinden light gun utility - I recommend you keep a separate copy dedicated to hypseus-singe games and their config&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 player Time Crisis 2 with Sinden Light Gun on PCSX2</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/time-crisis-2-1-player-sinden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/?p=6</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;21/6/25 - IMPORTANT NOTE: The method used in this guide does not currently offer the optimal experience for 2 players - there are problems with the 2 player dual cursor functionality! I therefore do not recommend this guide until I find time to research other methods and update it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a work in progress guide that I&amp;rsquo;m updating to be the &amp;lsquo;optimal&amp;rsquo; way of playing Time Crisis 2 on PC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epoch Light Gun Game Review</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/epoch-light-gun-game-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/epoch-light-gun-game-review/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I setup and played the &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/270510/EPOCH/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Epoch&amp;rsquo; rail-shooter game available on steam&lt;/a&gt;, with my Sinden light gun setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;negatives&#34;&gt;Negatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say, I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the mechanics of the game. The gameplay seemed pretty boring, and instead of one-shot-one-kill, you have to constantly &amp;lsquo;wear down&amp;rsquo; enemies through shooting at them, and moving out of their way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work very well on the Sinden light gun, as, although there are controls for moving - 4 buttons and a d-pad - on the gun, constantly having to switch to them and away from the &amp;lsquo;aim and fire&amp;rsquo; action does not work very well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Batsugun</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/batsugun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 03:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/?p=5630</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I played through the version of [https://store.steampowered.com/app/2023000/Batsugun/](Batsugun on Steam) on the arcade setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is part of the [Toaplan Arcade Shoot ‘Em Up Collection Vol.4](Toaplan Arcade Shoot &amp;lsquo;Em Up Collection Vol.4).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gunstar Heroes Review</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/gunstar-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/gunstar-heroes-pc</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years I have been stuck with a working megadrive with a Gunstar Heroes cartridge that works UP UNTIL A POINT, and then crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it were fully working, this Gunstar Heroes megadrive cartridge would be worth £250 at least at Ebay current prices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But more annoyingly, I have not been able to play the game properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Sega decided to discontinue the Sega Megadrive Collection on Steam, they offered a low price to buy all of the games, one of which was - you guessed it, Gunstar Heroes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Gaming Blog</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/new-gaming-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.davidcraddock.games/?p=1</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my new gaming blog, where I will write reviews of games I&amp;rsquo;ve played, game accessories I&amp;rsquo;ve bought, and anything else PC or console gaming-related that I can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is using the same setup as my main &lt;a href=&#34;https://davidcraddock.net&#34;&gt;https://davidcraddock.net&lt;/a&gt; blog - as in - it&amp;rsquo;s self-hosted, and uses the Hugo Go-based static blogging engine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PC and Console Gaming Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/Setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 19:52:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://davidcraddock.games/Setup</guid> 
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-main-workmediagaming-pc-studiolocal&#34;&gt;My Main Work/Media/Gaming PC &amp;lsquo;studio.local&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryzen 7 9800X 3D CPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIGABYTE B850 AORUS ELITE WIFI7 Motherboard with 2.5Gbits/sec internet and on-board Wifi7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be quiet! Straight Power 12 1000W power supply, ATX 3.0, 80 PLUS Platinum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooler Master MasterAir MA824 Stealth CPU Air Cooler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samsung 990 PRO NVMe M.2 SSD, 4 TB, PCIe 4.0, 7,450 MB/s read, 6,900 MB/s write, Internal SSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fractal Design North XL Charcoal Black Mesh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G.Skill Trident Z5 Neo EXPO RGB 64GB (2x32GB) DDR5 PC5-48000C30 6000MHz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ASUS GeForce RTX 4070 12G DUAL EVO OC Gaming Graphics Card - 2550MHz Boost Clock, GDDR6X, PCIe Gen 4, DLSS 3, HDMI 2.1a, 3 x DisplayPort 1.4a (Supports 4K &amp;amp; 8K HDR) * 12th Gen i7 CPU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1x 1TB SSD that I use as a system drive for legacy reasons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10Gb/sec fibre optic network card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;keyboard-and-mouse&#34;&gt;Keyboard and Mouse&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8Bitdo Retro Mechanical Keyboard, Bluetooth/2.4G/USB-C Hot Swappable Gaming Keyboard with 87 Keys, Dual Super Buttons and Super Stick for Windows and Android - ISO UK Layout - C64 Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8BitDo Retro 18 Mechanical Numpad, Supports Calculator Mode, Bluetooth/2.4G/Wired Numpad for Windows and Android - C64 Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LOFREE TOUCH PBT Wireless Mouse with USB receiver, Bluetooth, Wired Connection, Rechargeable, 4000 DPI with OLED Screen Compatible with glass surface for Mac Windows PC Notebook/Block Retro White Gray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;monitor-and-other-accessories&#34;&gt;Monitor and Other accessories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ASUS ROG Swift OLED PG32UCDM gaming monitor ― 32-inch 4K QD-OLED panel, 240Hz, 0.03ms (GTG), G-SYNC compatible, custom heatsink, graphene film, uniform brightness, 99% DCI-P3, True 10-bit, 90 W Type-C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;29 inch &amp;lsquo;Tate Mode&amp;rsquo; portrait mode LCD VA 144hz refresh gaming monitor with Gsync&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x Genelec 8020 DPM speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logi USB headset with noise cancelling microphone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logitech Key light for web cam calls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LogiTech C920 web cam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R0de Procaster mic with boom, roll cage and muffler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network cabinet with rack-mounted Mikrotik fibreoptic 10Gb/sec router, switch and a Presonus 1824i USB-c sound interface that is connected to the PC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;ergonomic-equipment&#34;&gt;Ergonomic Equipment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexispot E7Pro Motorised Desk with 2x ergonomic monitor stand arms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexispot BS14 ergonomic chair with headrest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexispot standing desk mat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wooden rocker balance board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;360 style balance board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fenge Dual Monitor Stand, Monitor Stands Riser for 2 monitors, 42.5 Inch Wood Desk Shelf with Storage Organizer and Cable Management for Office Desk Accessories Black&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FIFINE Microphone Arm Stand, Boom Arm Stand with Desk Mount Clamp, Screw Adapter, Cable Management, Suspension Scissor Mic Stand for Boom Stick Microphone, for Podcast Streaming Gaming Studio-BM88 (for R0de mic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quntis Monitor Light bar with RGB Backlight, 40cm Computer Monitor Lamp with Dimmer and Color Temperature, LED Touch Control Gaming Screen Light No Screen Glare and Eye Protection for Home Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;media-pc-software&#34;&gt;Media PC Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dbPowerAmp CD Ripper (lifetime licence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MakeMKV for ripping CDs and Blu-rays (lifetime licence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AnyDVD HD (lifetime licence) for ripping DVDs and Blu-rays&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4K Video Downloader (lifetime licence) for ripping videos from Youtube etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imagemagik for creating GIFs and command line batch graphics manipulation and conversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FFMPEG for command line batch video manipulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movavai Video Editor 2022&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony Vegas 19 Video Editor for more complex video edits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aseprite Pixel Graphics and Animated Gif Editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sonarworks SoundID Reference - speaker and headphones environmental EQ software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audacity Audio Editor for editing and mastering mixes uploaded to Mixcloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hye Sync (official app) for syncing Phillips Hue lights to movies, games, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PlexAmp and Plex for streaming audio and video from my Plex server at highest quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VLC for video playback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HandBrake for transcoding and compressing video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OBS Studio (open source)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolume Avenue 7 for visuals for my DJ stream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolume Wire for creating custom beat-synced visualisations for my stream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paint.NET open source graphics program for simple crops and photo editing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aiseesoft Blu-ray Player (lifetime licence) for playing unripped Blu-rays on my PC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bome MIDI Translator Classic (lifetime licence) for translating MIDI events to key presses - useful for complex streaming setups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various free emulation tools for decrypting/anti-DRMing copies of video game console optical disks and getting them in a playable state for use in an emulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reaper DAW (shareware licence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ableton Live 11 Suite DAW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filebot for renaming and organising media files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-gaming-laptop-legionlocal&#34;&gt;My Gaming Laptop &amp;rsquo;legion.local&amp;rsquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lenovo Legion 5-15IAH 2022&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i7 12th Gen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;64GB DDR5 RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2x 2TB NVME M.2 4th Gen SSDs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nvidia Laptop 3070TI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooling Gaming Laptop Pad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming-setup&#34;&gt;Gaming Setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I share this setup between the Media PC and the Gaming Laptop.
I have a 4K HDR KVM switch and a USB 3.0 KVM switch so I can quickly switch between the two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Home Retro Arcade Setup</title>
      <link>https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/Arcade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://davidcraddock.games/Arcade</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/Arcade/lightguns.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/Arcade/4.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted an arcade machine in my home. But I could never really afford one, in terms of time and space. Recently I thought to myself, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not getting any younger&amp;rdquo;. So I built an arcade setup mostly just using the things I already had in the home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidcraddockgames.github.io/Arcade/1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;games&#34;&gt;Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ROMs I have are all stored on my file server upstairs. I can get around a 3gbits/sec connection via my 10gbits/sec home network, so there is no performance &amp;lsquo;hit&amp;rsquo; in streaming them off the network drive - it has similar speed and latency to a physical drive. Which is handy, because my ROM collection is way too big for the storage on my gaming PC.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
